Guide to the Inge Morath Photographs and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1896-2001; Series I; 136.99; (550 boxes)
  - Photographic Prints
    - Work Prints
      - Spain
        - Seville, 1987 (Box 255)
          1987-12
        - Camino de Santiago, 1998 (Box 255)
          1998-06
        - Art and Architecture (Box 256)
          1954-18, 1954-09, 1955-30, 1956-12
        - 1950's Spain, 1954-1955 (Box 257)
          1954-18, 1955-21, 1955-26
        - La Alberca, Las Hurdes, Barcelona, Madrid, Mallorca, Northern Spain, 1954-1956 (Box 258)
          1954-18, 1955-09, 1955-10, 1956-12
        - Spain, 1954-1958; 3 (Box 259)
        - Madrid, The Feria in Sevilla, Holy Week in Sevilla, 1986-1988; 2 (Box 259)
          1986-08, 1987-12, 1988-06
        - Camino de Santiago (Box 259)
        - Corrida in Barcelona, Madrid, Verbena de San Isidro, Bullfights de San Isidro, Romeria del Rocio, Vigo, Calicia, Spain, 1954-1956; 2 (Box 260)
          1954-18, 1955-11, 1955-12, 1955-13, 1955-31, 1955-25
      - Steinberg, Saul, 2
        - Saul Steinberg, 1959-1980; 2 (Box 260)
          1961-04, 1962-32, 1967-17, 1980-10
        - Saul Steinberg, Kentucky, 1962-1965 (Box 261)
          Steinberg: 1961-04, 1962-32; Kentucky: 1965-08
      - West Point, 2001 (Box 262)
        West Point: 2001-07
      - Mixed Countries
        - Austria/Italy, 1984 (Box 263)
          1984-13
        - Berlin, pictures of friends, undated (Box 263)
        - Berlin, 1996 (Box 263)
          1996-03
        - "Broken Glass," New Haven, New York rehearsal pics, 1994 (Box 263)
          1994-03
        - Zoe Caldwell and Christopher Plummer, 1967 (Box 263)
          1967-09
        - France, 1955-1993 (Box 263)
          1955-21, 1958-07, 1959-10, 1993-11
        - Germany, 1996; 2 (Box 263)
          1996-03, 1996-15
        - Graz, 1984-2001 (Box 263)
          1984-13, 1992-07, 2001-01
        - India, and Bharatpur, Nepal, 1993 (Box 263)
        - Iran (Box 263)
        - Jerusalem, 1977 (Box 264)
        - Lebanon, Tehran, 1956 (Box 264)
        - Portuguese village, Lisbon, 1956 (Box 264)
        - Prague, 1994 (Box 264)
          1994-14
        - Romania, 1958-1994 (Box 264)
          1958-09, 1958-15, 1958-16, 1961-18, 1993-09, 1994-12
        - Russia, 1965-1990 (Box 264)
          1965-05, 1967-11, 1985-14, 1986-13, 1987-06, 1988-07, 1989-11, 1989-17, 1990-04
        - Russia book, 1989 (Box 264)
          1989-11
        - South Africa, 1955 (Box 265)
          1955-33
        - Thailand, 1970 (Box 265)
          1970-05
        - Tunisia, 1956-1960 (Box 265)
        - United States
          - Kentucky, 1965 (Box 265)
            1965-08
          - Los Angeles, 1987 (Box 265)
        - Vienna, 1978-1979 (Box 265)
          Vienna 1978-02, 1979-01
        - West Point, 2001 (Box 265)
          2001-07
        - Miscellaneous mixed countries, 1965-1996 (Box 265)
        - Cambodia, 1970 (Box 266)
          1970-04
        - China color conversions, undated (Box 266)
        - Georgia, USSR, 1967-11 (Box 266)
        - Hong Kong, 1970 (Box 266)
          1970-05, 1970-06
        - Israel/Jerusalem, 1972 (Box 266)
          1972-02
        - Japan, 1970 (Box 267)
        - Portuguese village, Lisbon, mouth of Tajo River, 1956 (Box 267)
        - Thailand, 1970 (Box 267)
        - United States, 1965 (Box 267)
        - Writers and artists, 1965 (Box 267)
        - Cuba, Danube, Vienna, 1955-2000 (Box 268)
          Cuba: 1958-09, 2000-05; Danube: 1955-05, 1958-18, 1975-09; Vienna: 1975-09, 1978-02
        - Paris, China, Spain, Russia (resin-coated paper), 1955-1989 (Box 269)
          1955-09, 1955-21, 1965-05, 1967-11, 1987-06
        - Paris, China, Spain, Russia (resin-coated paper), 1955-1990 (Box 270)
          1967-11, 1986-13, 1990-04
        - Mixed countries, 1954-1993 (Box 271)
        - Miscellaneous, 1976-1993 (Box 271)
      - Miscellaneous
        - Correspondence, 1974, 1987 (Box 272)
          For preservation purposes, the prints were removed from their container. The empty container is stored in Box 279
        - "Le book", 1982 (Box 272)
        - Catherinettes, Paris, Lake Constance, Refugee Camps, Misfits, Dr. Young, 1958-1976; 6 (Box 272)
          1958-19, 1959-21, 1959-25, 1960-01, 1960-16, 1976-04
        - Russia, First Issyk-Voz, The Moscow Forum, Portraits of Journalist Barbara Ungeheuer, Roxbury, 1986-1991; 23 (Box 272)
          1986-13, 1987-06. 1989-20, 1991-01
        - Connecticut, William Styron, 1964-1975; 4 (Box 273)
          1964-06, 1965-09, 1967-01, 1970-01, 1971-01, 1973-02, 1975-01
        - Connecticut: McCarthy Campaign, Creation of the World and Other Business, rehearsal shots, Architect I.M. Pei in Peking, 1967-1979; 3 (Box 274)
          1967-01, 1968-05, 1970-01, 1971-01, 1972-06, 1974-01, 1976-01, 1979-06
        - Bankers Trust Building, Connecticut, 1963--1979; 2 (Box 275)
          1963-01, 1968-01, 1975-01
        - Italy, Refugee Camps, Russia, " Timebends booktour", 1954-1987 (Box 275)
          1954-10, 1960-01, 1965-05, 1987-29
        - Russia, Kosygin at the United Nations, Venezuela, Connecticut, Takarazuka Theater and School, Japan, Twin Towers memorial, 1954-2001; 7 (Box 276)
          1967-11, 1981-06, 1967-07, 1968-01, 1977-11, 1977-12, 2001-11
        - "Persia," Refugee Camps, Russia, 1956-1996 (Box 277)
          1956-09, 1960-01,1965-05, 1967-11
        - Russia, Berlin, 1965-1998 (Box 278)
          1965-05, 1967-11, 1998-14
        - Empty box, undated (Box 279)
          For preservation purposes, the prints were removed from their container
    - Exhibition/Modern Prints
      Exhibition/Modern prints (approximately 1480), also known as Lifetime prints, represent archival quality photographic prints on fiber paper primarily 11 by 14 inches with a small group of 16 by 20 inches made by fine art printers under Morath's direction for exhibition and sale in galleries from circa 1985 until her death.
      - Exhibition/Modern Prints, 1953-1954 (Box 280)
      - Exhibition/Modern prints, 1955-1956 (Box 281)
      - Exhibition/Modern prints, 1957-1959 (Box 282)
      - Exhibition/Modern prints, 1960-1961 (Box 283)
      - Exhibition/Modern prints, 1962-1966 (Box 284)
      - Exhibition/Modern prints, 1967-1979 (Box 285)
      - Exhibition/Modern prints, 1980-1989 (Box 286)
      - Exhibition/Modern prints, 1990-1995 (Box 287)
      - Exhibition/Modern prints, 1996-1999 (Box 288)
      - Exhibition/Modern prints, 2000-2001 (Box 289)
      - Exhibition/Modern prints, 1950-1955 (Box 290)
      - Exhibition/Modern prints, 1955-1959 (Box 291)
      - Exhibition/Modern prints, 1960s-1969 (Box 292)
      - Exhibition/Modern prints, 1970-1990 (Box 293)
      - Exhibition/Modern prints, 1950-2002 (Box 294)
    - Estate Prints
      Estate prints (approximately 100) are high-quality prints made after Morath's death in 2002. These posthumously created prints include images that Morath did not print during her lifetime.
      It also includes 53 digital ink jet prints, 11 by 14 inches, of color photographs by Morath.
      - Estate prints, 2001 (Box 295)
      - Estate prints, 2001 (Box 296)
      - Estate prints, 2001 (Box 297)
      - Photographic The Misfits, "Arthur Miller in Paris" test prints for Inge Morath, The Road to Reno, (Göttingen: Steidl, 2006)", circa 2005; 5 (Box 525)
        1960-15, 1960-16
    - Subject Reference Prints
      Arranged by subject.
      Project files represent enlargements probably used by Morath for editorial purposes, such as planning monographs and exhibitions. The primarily fiber paper prints measure 5 by 7 inches and 8 by 10 inches, with occasional prints measuring 11 by 14 inches. Many have notes by Morath on versos.
      During initial processing, library staff rehoused the following subject groups: China, Cuba, Connecticut, and New York City, as well as a portion of the Portraits.
      Notes in the guide for this group of material include represented story numbers when easily discerned by library staff.
      - China, 1978; 23 (Box 298)
      - China, 1978; 26 (Box 299)
      - China, 1979-1983; 43 (Box 300)
        1979-5, 1979-6, 1983-4
      - China, 1983; 25 (Box 301)
        1983-8, 1983-9
      - Connecticut, 1962-1964; 23 (Box 301)
        1964-4, 1964-6, 1964-8
      - Connecticut, 1965-1969; 47 (Box 302)
        1965-01, 1965-09, 1967-1, 1968-01, 1968-05, 1969-01,
      - Connecticut, 1970-1972; 57 (Box 303)
        1970-011971-01, 1972-01
      - Connecticut, 1973-1977; 47 (Box 304)
        1973-01, 1973-021974-01, 1975-01, 1977-01
      - Cuba, 2000; 19 (Box 305)
        2000-05
      - New York, 1970-1997; 10 (Box 305)
        1970-07, 1982-05, 1982-08, 1973-07, 1977-01,
      - New York, 1990-1997; 52 (Box 306)
        1990-01, 1994-08, 1995-01, 1996-16, 1997-03, 1997-04
      - New York, 1997-2001; 25 (Box 307)
        1997-04, 1998-02, 1998-03, 1999-06, 2000-01, 2000-10, 2000-11
      - Portraits, 1953-1958; 27 (Box 307)
        1953-04, 1954-07, 1954-08, 1954-22, 1955-24, 1955-29, 1955-31, 1956-26, 1958-03, 1958-05, 1958-07
      - Portraits, 1958-1986; 70 (Box 308)
      - Portraits, 1986-1992; 65 (Box 309)
        1986-13, 1987-06, 1987-07, 1987-08, 1987-26, 1987-28, 1988-05, 1989-14, 1991-02, 1991-04, 1991-09, 1992-01
      - Portraits, 1992-1995; 36 (Box 310)
      - Portraits, 1995-2001; 42 (Box 311)
      - Austria, Hungary, Romania, Uruguay, 1953-1989 (Box 312)
      - United States, Danube, Regensburg, 1954-2001 (Box 313)
      - Miscellaneous Travel, 1960-2001 (Box 314)
      - Moscow, 1987-1989 (Box 315)
      - Paris, Venice, London, Saxony, 1949-1997 (Box 316)
      - Slovenia, Romania, Connecticut, 1958-2001 (Box 317)
      - Saul Steinberg, Rebecca Miller Play, Moscow, Kentucky, 1959 (Box 318)
      - Spain 50's, Romania, 1954-1958 (Box 319)
      - Spain: Camino de Santiago, Navalcán, 1954 (Box 320)
      - Spain: Pamplona, Seville, 1954-1988 (Box 321)
      - Vienna, Ireland, Italy, Dublin, Alaska, Venezuela, London, 1953-1996 (Box 322)
      - Venice, Vienna, 1955-1989 (Box 323)
        1955-32, 1980-09
    - Copy Prints
      Arranged chronologically.
      Copy prints (more than 5,500) consist of enlargements usually made on resin-coated paper, chiefly 8 by 10 inches and 11 by 14 inches, which Morath sent to publishers for reproduction use. These prints include examples of inscriptions and signatures by Morath and ink stamps on versos, as well as deteriorating adhesive labels.
      - 1950s, 1952-1956 (Box 324)
      - 1950s, 1956-1958 (Box 325)
      - 1950s, 1958-1959 (Box 326)
      - 1960s (Box 327)
      - 1960s, 1960-1965 (Box 328)
      - 1965-1979 (Box 329)
      - 1980s, 1980-1986 (Box 330)
      - 1980s, 1987-1989 (Box 331)
      - Resin-coated paper prints, 1954-1970 (Box 332)
      - Signed and or captioned by IM, 1954-1986 (Box 333)
      - Prints to research, circa 1990 (Box 334)
      - Damaged, 1953-1985 (Box 335)
      - Damaged, 1987-1989 (Box 336)
      - Damaged, 1988-1989 (Box 337)
    - Mixed Prints
      This group of material includes various prints of images by Morath, including mounted prints and color prints.
      - Glamour school, Fifth Avenue, 1958 (Box 338)
        1958-23
      - Bedouin dancer south of Baghdad, Iraq, 1956 (Box 338)
        1956-10c
      - Arthur Miller, 1963, 1994 (Box 338)
        1963-20
      - Sleigh drawn horses, Moscow, 1965 (Box 338)
      - Saul Steinberg, Masks, 1961-1962 (Box 338)
        1961-04, 1962-32
      - Llama in New York City, 1957 (Box 338)
        1957-01
      - The Misfits, 1960 (Box 338)
        1960-16
      - Mercedes de Formica, Evgeny Yevtushenko and wife, Olga Carlisle, resin-coated paper prints, 1955-1988 (Box 338)
        1955-35, 1968-04, 1972-01, 1988-07
      - "To be researched", undated (Box 338)
      - Gaza, 1960 (Box 339)
        1960-01
      - Russia Book
        - "Train station to Russia", 1965 (Box 339)
        - Horses, 1965 (Box 339)
        - Moscow, 1965-1967 (Box 339)
        - Leningrad, 1965, 1967 (Box 339)
        - Ballet dancers, Leningrad State School, 1965 (Box 339)
        - Russia, 1965-1989 (Box 339)
        - Russia project, undated (Box 339)
        - Novodevichiĭ cemetery, 1967 (Box 340)
        - Georgia, 1967 (Box 340)
        - Novgorod, 1967 (Box 340)
        - Outside Moscow, 1967 (Box 340)
        - Pereslavlʹ-Zalesskiĭ, 1967 (Box 340)
        - Samarkand, 1967 (Box 340)
        - Tretyakov Gallery, Moscow, 1965 (Box 340)
      - Collected Exhibition and Vintage Prints, 1960-1967
        - Refugee Camps, 1960 (Box 341)
          1960-01, 1962-32, 1963-20, 1967-11
        - Saul Steinberg Book, Stevenson at the United Nations, A View from the Bridge film, 1961 (Box 341)
          1961-04, 1961-10, 1961-11
        - Saul Steinberg Masks, 1962 (Box 341)
          1962-32
        - Alexander Calder, 1963 (Box 341)
        - Russia, 1965 (Box 341)
        - Russia, 1967 (Box 341)
        - Yevgeny Aleksandrovich Yevtushenko, poet, 1968 (Box 342)
          1968-04
        - Connecticut, Cambodia, 1970 (Box 342)
          1970-01, 1970-04
        - Sculptor Alexander Calder, Novelist Jerzy Kosiński (Box 342)
        - China, 1978 (Box 342)
        - Boat on the Yangtze River (China), Playing for Time stage scene with Vanessa Redgrave, 1979 (Box 342)
          1979-05, 1979-16
      - Lavazza advertisement, undated (Box 343)
        Includes box
      - Venice, London, Yugoslavia, 1958, undated (Box 343)
      - Eastern Europe, color and black-and-white, undated (Box 343)
      - Portraits, Spain, 1967-1989 (Box 344)
      - Russia, Romania (Box 344)
        Includes some contact sheets
      - China
        1978-12, 1983-09
        - Chekiang, China, 1978 (Box 345)
        - Foshan Ancestral temple, 1978 (Box 345)
        - Guilin, 1978 (Box 345)
        - Nanking, 1978 (Box 345)
        - Peking Summer Palace, 1978 (Box 345)
        - Peking, 1978; 3 (Box 346)
        - Shanghai, 1978; 2 (Box 346)
        - Xian, 1978 (Box 346)
        - Yan'an Shi, 1978 (Box 346)
      - "Cut up contacts", 1987 (Box 346)
      - Color prints
        - Peking, Yangtze River, China, 1979 (Box 347)
          Mounted prints, 1979-05
        - Latin America: Brazil, Peru, Panama, Santo Domingo de Guzmán, undated (Box 348)
        - Mongolia, undated (Box 348)
        - Eastern Europe, [Russia?], undated (Box 348)
          Includes black-and-white prints.
        - Empty box, undated (Box 348)
        - Guambiano Indians of Columbia, Middle East, circa 1960-1970 (Box 349)
        - Stone relief of woman, [Iraq?], circa 1960-1970 (Box 349)
        - Ingeborg ten Haeff, painter, New York, 1984 (Box 349)
        - Paul Elsenboss, writer, Connecticut, 1984 (Box 349)
        - Marilyn Monroe and Clark Gable, "The Misfits", 1960 (Box 349)
        - Liv Ullman, unidentified room with painting, circa 1980 (Box 349)
        - Rebecca Miller, circa 1984 (Box 349)
        - Marilyn Monroe: "The Misfits", 1960 (Box 349)
        - Mixed color, undated (Box 349)
        - Under 8x10 color prints, undated (Box 350)
    - Oversize Prints
      Arranged with Exhibition/Modern Prints followed by other oversize prints.
      This group of material includes photographic prints that measure larger than 11 by 14 inches.
      - Exhibition/Modern Prints
        - Stone wall arch with lions, undated (Box 351 (Oversize))
        - Pamplona, 1954 (Box 351 (Oversize))
          1954-24
        - Generation Women, 1955 (Box 351 (Oversize))
          1955-35
        - Earth goddess statue, circa 1960-1980 (Box 351 (Oversize))
        - Sitting deer statue, circa 1960-1980 (Box 351 (Oversize))
        - Fifth Avenue, 1958 (Box 351 (Oversize))
        - Lifetime prints, 1950-2002 (Box 351 (Oversize))
      - Refugee camps, 1960 (Box 352 (Oversize))
      - Mrs. Eveleigh Nash, sculptor, 1953, undated (Box 352 (Oversize))
        1953-04
      - "The Misfits", 1960 (Box 352 (Oversize))
      - Spanish dancer, bullfighter, 1954-1958 (Box 352 (Oversize))
      - Saul Steinberg, Masks, 1959-1962 (Box 352 (Oversize))
        1959-02, 1962-32
      - The Misfits oversize contact sheets, 1960 (Box 352 (Oversize))
      - Spain, oversize contact sheets, circa 1954-1958 (Box 352 (Oversize))
      - Four mounted prints in a portfolio box, undated (Box 353 (Oversize))
    - Framed Prints
      This group of material consists of framed prints that measure 20 by 15 inches.
      - Louise Bourgeois with sculpture, To Fall on Dead Ears, 1991 (Box 354 (Oversize))
      - Alex Katz, painter and engraver in his studio, 1995 (Box 355 (Oversize))
      - George Segal, sculptor and painter, New Jersey, 1995 (Box 356 (Oversize))
      - Roy Lichtenstein in his studio, 1997 (Box 357 (Oversize))
      - Andre Charles, a graffiti artist on Houston Street, 1998 (Box 358 (Oversize))
  - Color Transparencies
    Organized under four headings: Personal Slides Set, Magnum New York Slides Set, Panoramic Transparencies, and General Slides.
    This series chiefly includes 35-millimeter color slides (approximately 46,000) that document Morath's color photography during the first two decades of her career and complement her black-and-white images of the same period. It also includes examples of color transparencies and occasional color and black-and-white negatives with variant dimensions including 2 by 2 inches, 4 by 5 inches, and 8 by 10 inches.
    - Personal Slides Set
      This material consists of Morath's personal set of color transparencies, chiefly 35-millimeter slides, identified by the Inge Morath Foundation.
      - Death of a Salesman, rehearsal slides, "Salesman in Beijing," publicity, Magnum distribution captions for Beijing, articles, 1983 (Box 359)
        1983-09
      - Death of a Salesman, Beijing, 1983 (Box 360)
      - After the Fall, The American Clock, Up from Paradise, Dustin Hoffman, Death of a Salesman, Everybody Wins, 1963-1989 (Box 361)
        1963-26, 1982-13, 1983-18, 1989-13
      - Arthur Miller, Portraits, Roxbury, Barbados, Arthur Miller posters, The Crucible, 1962-1995 (Box 362)
        1962-15, 1963-23, 1965-05, 1972-01, 1981-02, 1995-01, 1995-14
      - Miller, special photos, (personal family) Inge in early Spain, Audie Murphy, The Unforgiven, 1956-1996 (Box 363)
        1962-15, 1965-08, 1970-01, 1977-01, 1975-09, 1978-01, 1987-07, 1989-01, 1995-01, 1996-01
      - Arthur Miller, Israel, Roxbury, 1977-1995 (Box 364)
        1985-06, 1989-01, 1995-05
      - Millers II. Portraits: Arthur Vol IV., 1961-1995 (Box 365)
        1961-08, 1962-35, 1962-43, 1967-01, 1970-01, 1977-01, 1991-01, 1995-02
      - Rebecca Miller movies: Angela and Florence, 1990-1994 (Box 366)
        1990-09, 1994-08
      - Rebecca Miller, 1963-1989 (Box 367)
        1963-04, 1967-01, 1969-01, 1970-03, 1972-01, 1973-02, 1975-01, 1977-01, 1978-01, 1980-01, 1981-01, 1989-16
      - Rebecca Miller, 1967-1995 (Box 368)
        1967-01, 1975-09, 1977-02, 1980-01, 1989-02, 1990-01, 1993-01, 1994-08, 1995-01, 1995-04
      - Movies: The Crucible and Playing for Time, 1992-1995 (Box 369)
        1995-14
      - Black-and-white portfolio slides, 1953-1983 (Box 370)
      - New Portfolio, 1954-1997 (Box 371)
        1958-05, 1963-20, 1997-02
      - Flowers, Dupes, In the Country, 1962-1990 (Box 372)
        1962-31, 1963-23, 1964-06, 1965-16, 1965-17, 1970-01, 1973-02, 1975-11, 1977-07, 1977-01, 1990-01
      - 4 by 5 negatives, black-and-white and color, 1958-1967 (Box 373)
        Includes story list of negatives measuring 4 by 5 inches
      - Artists and Personalities Vol. I, 1959-1988 (Box 374)
        Accompanied by a list of subjects
      - Artists and Personalities Vol. II, 1954-1986 (Box 375)
      - Artists and Personalities Vol. III, 1963-1995 (Box 376)
      - Places, churches, cemeteries, house interiors Vol. V, 1965-1975 (Box 377)
        1965-09, 1967-01, 1970-01, 1971-01, 1972-01, 1973-02, 1975-01
      - Places, churches, cemeteries, house interiors Vol. VI, 1970-1975 (Box 378)
        1970-01, 1971-01, 1974-01, 1973-01, 1975-01
      - The Seasons Vol III, 1963-1977 (Box 379)
        1963-04, 1966-07, 1967-01, 1968-01, 1969-01, 1971-01, 1972-01, 1974-01, 1975-01, 1977-01
      - Fairs, celebrations, animals Vol. IX, 1965-1991 (Box 380)
        1965-05, 1967-01, 1970-01, 1971-01, 1973-01, 1974-01, 1975-11
      - Fairs, celebrations, animals Vol. X, 1965-1975 (Box 381)
        1965-09, 1970-01, 1971-01, 1972-01
      - Poems, dreams, nudes, Russian interpretations Vol. XI, 1962-1977 (Box 382)
        1962-35, 1970-01, 1971-01, 1972-01, 1977-01
      - Europe
        - Austria: Gottweig, Krems, Vienna, Graz, Salzburg, 1958-1991 (Box 383)
          1958-01, 1958-17, 1961-18, 1979-04, 1991-03
        - Italy, Belgium, Athens, London, Ireland, 1953-1993 (Box 384)
          1953-03, 1954-11, 1954-19, 1955-32, 1956-32, 1961-16, 1964-01, 1978-03, 1980-05, 1993-06
        - Darmstadt, Berlin, 1983-1991 (Box 385)
          1983-19, 1989-18, 1991-02
        - 1989 Color: Berlin Wall, Altzella, Bredow, Korin; New BW Portfolio, 1953-1996 (Box 386)
          1953-04, 1954-08, 1954-24, 1955-03, 1955-21, 1958-09, 1960-04, 1960-15, 1961-10, 1969-03, 1970-01, 1973-08, 1983-07, 1985-02, 1987-24, 1995-13, 1996-03
        - Danube: Yugoslavia, Romania, CSR Germany, Tromp, 1958-1995 (Box 387)
          1958-15, 1958-16, 1959-26, 1961-18, 1995-12
        - Vienna, Lower Austria, 1957-1980 (Box 388)
          1957-16, 1961-18, 1978-02, 1975-09, 1980-13
        - Danube, All color, Countries: Bratislava, Trnava, Slovakia; Austro Hungarian border, Budapest, Krems, 1958-1995 (Box 389)
          1958-16, 1959-26, 1961-18, 1975-09, 1993-09, 1994-04, 1994-12, 1995-12
        - Danube Color: Bucharest, Călărasi, Tulcea, Romania; Sulina, Histria, Black Sea; Bogenberg, Regensburg, Germany, 1958-1994 (Box 390)
          1958-09, 1958-16, 1959-26, 1975-09, 1993-09, 1994-04
        - La Alberca, Las Hurdes, Romeria del Rocio, Northern Spain, El Greco, Toledo, Spain, 1954-1962 (Box 391)
          1954-18, 1955-09, 1955-13, 1955-31, 1956-12, 1957-07, 1961-32, 1962-15
        - Spain: Barcelona, Madrid, The Feria in Sevilla, The Town of Ronda, 1986-1988 (Box 392)
          1986-09, 1987-11, 1987-12
        - Spain: Feria in Sevilla, Holy Week in Seville, Macarena procession, view from Triana, Andalusia, Madrid, Ronda, fighting bulls, 1987-1992 (Box 393)
          1987-12, 1988-06, 1992-04
      - Russia
        - Russia Portfolio, 1965-1989 (Box 394)
          1965-05, 1967-11, 1988-07, 1989-11, 1989-17
        - First Issyk-Voz, Inge Morath show in Moscow, building of Union of Photojournalists, trip to Moscow, Kalinin (Tver), Vilnius and Launus in Lithuania, visit to Vladimir, Susdal and Armenia, 1965-1989 (Box 395)
          1965-05, 1967-11, 1986-13, 1987-07, 1988-07, 1989-11, 1989-17. Includes four 4 by 5 transparencies
        - Trip to the Soviet Union (with Progress Publishers), Moscow museums, Gorky Park, Leningrad, Pasternak house, Crimea, Yalta, Black Sea, Rostov Velikiĭ, Visit to Vladimir and Susdal and Armenia, 1987-1989 (Box 396)
          1987-07, 1989-17
        - Moscow and Lithuania, Vladimir, Susdal and Armenia, First Issyk-Voz, Garni, Samarkand, Moscow sleigh pulling horse, 1965-1989 (Box 397)
          1965-05, 1967-11, 1986-13, 1987-07, 1988-07, 1989-123
        - Zagorsk, Moscow, Rostov Velikiĭ, Novgorod region, Red Square, Kremlin, Mikhail Gorbachev, Stanislavsky Museum, Kalinin, Vilnius, Lithuania, Pasternak, Illustration for Pasternak poem, 1965-1989 (Box 398)
          1965-05, 1967-11, 1974-01, 1986-13, 1989-11
      - Egypt
        - Egypt: Cairo-Nile, Giza, Ṣaqqārah, Abydos, Karnak, Temple of Luxor, 1981 (Box 399)
        - Egypt: Medinet Habu Site, Temple of Hatshepsut, Valley of the Queens, Esna region, Aswan Dam, Philae, Lake Nasser, Valley of the Kings, 1981 (Box 400)